天地伊始  一片混沌
In the beginning, there was darkness.
忽地一声巨响
And then-- Bang!
时空与物质由此而生
Giving birth to an endless, expanding existence
继而不断发展  永无止尽
of time, space, and matter.
每天都有新发现解开其中
Every day, new discoveries are unlocking
神秘莫测  令人大开眼界  却又致命的秘密
the mysterious, the mind-blowing, the deadly secrets
这就是我们的
of a place we call
宇宙
the universe.
成千上万的人声称亲眼见过不明飞行物
Thousands of witnesses have claimed to see UFOs.
他们对此现象的描述是惊人的相似
And their accounts are often strikingly similar.
坠落的飞盘  加上尸体残骸
You have a crashed saucer, but also some crashed bodies.
还有政府介入的掩饰行为
You have government cover-up.
主流科学一致认为目前证据不足
Mainstream science says the evidence just isn't there.
从不明飞行物到外星飞船是一个很大的跨越
It's a big jump between a UFO and an extraterrestrial spacecraft.
但如果不明飞行物的确是外星飞船
But if UFOs were really extraterrestrial craft,
那其中又隐藏了何种令人匪夷所思的技术
what kind of mind-bending technologies would we find under the hood?
外星飞船一定要有特殊技术
You'd have to have some sort of technology that was capable
才能抵消惯性作用
of canceling the effects of inertia.
不明飞行物神秘面纱后的
When it comes to Unidentified Flying Objects,
真实面目究竟是什么呢
what is the real deal?
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：nonopig  Shinstar  Angelica  咕叽   时间轴：二氧化碳
宇                   宙
不明飞行物的真面目
校对：傲骨   咕叽 后期&总监：丢丢
■
对于无数追随者来说
For millions of believers,
这一切始于1947年6月24日
it all began on June 24, 1947.
商人飞行员肯尼斯・阿诺德当时正在
A businessman and pilot named Kenneth Arnold is flying solo
华盛顿州的雷尼尔山附近独自飞行
near Mount Rainier, Washington.
突然  他看到九个飞行器组成一队
Suddenly he sees a group of nine aircraft
以惊人的速度飞行
moving at incredible speeds.
这些飞行器高度反光
They were highly reflective,
并以超音速列队飞行
and they were flying at supersonic speeds,
它们还会突然改变航线
in formation, changing course abruptly.
以当时的技术无法达到该速度
The speeds were unattainable at the time.
威廉・R・阿尔舒勒
《不明飞行物之科学》作者
那时喷气式飞机和超音速飞机还未问世
This was before the age of jets and certainly supersonic jets.
身为训练有素的飞行员
Being a trained pilot,
为了确认自己看到的是飞行器
he did several things to corroborate their existence
而不是某种大气效应
to make sure he wasn't seeing some kind of atmospheric effect.
他摆动自己的头  改变机身的角度
He changed his-- his head angle. He changed the aircraft angle.
凯文・格雷瑟尔
行星学家
他甚至调整了飞机位置
He even positioned the aircraft such that
让白雪作为这群飞行器的背景
there was a light snow in the background behind the objects,
而在白雪的映衬下  这群飞行器显得很暗
and they appeared dark against a light surface.
但就在阿诺德设法接近时  不明物体消失了
Before Arnold can maneuver closer, the objects are gone.
这算得上是现代史无前例的发现
It was basically unprecedented in modern times.
从未有人见过类似的物体
No one had seen anything like this.
后来在他讲述事件时
In the days that follow, newspaper reporters misquote Arnold,
飞碟
肯尼斯・阿诺德 飞碟到来
记者误引了阿诺德的话
as he tries to make sense of the incident.
当时他说它的飞行方式像碟子在水上漂
In fact, he said it moved like saucers skipping on water.
赛斯・肖斯塔科
地外文明搜索研究所
而记者把这个意思理解错了
Now, of course, the reporter kind of messed that up
而报道说它们看起来像碟子
in reporting it and said that they looked like saucers.
"飞碟"一词由此而生
The term "Flying saucer" is born.
飞碟
阿诺德的发现首开现代不明飞行物现象的先河
And Arnold's encounter launches the modern UFO phenomenon.
几周后  即在1947年的夏天
Weeks later, in the summer of 1947,
在新墨西哥州的罗斯威尔附近发生了
perhaps the most famous incident involving an Unidentified Flying Object
史上最著名的不明飞行物事件
is reported near Roswell, New Mexico.
罗斯威尔事件是典型的不明飞行物现象
Roswell's become the poster child of the UFO phenomenon,
因其具备所有必要因素
because it has all the necessary ingredients.
坠落的飞碟  加上尸体残骸
You have a crashed saucer, but also some crashed bodies.
还有政府介入  他们绝对隐瞒了实情
You have government cover-up. There was some sort of cover-up.
当局发布的是虚假信息
There was misinformation given out by the authorities.
澳大利亚空军在罗斯威尔地区牧场上空发现飞碟
消息最初是从空军那边传出的
The original account put out by the air force at the time was
说这就是来自外太空的飞碟
that this was a flying saucer of alien origin.
瑞米将军否认了罗斯威尔飞碟
但没过多久  这个说法就被否认了
And then later, very quickly, was denied, and the story then
改称这是个坠毁的气象气球
was that this was a weather balloon which had crashed and
上面没有载人
that there were no occupants on board
说有外星人更是无稽之谈
and that there was nothing extraterrestrial about it.
发现飞碟的农场主后悔自己说出了这个事情
其他目击者宣称看到了坠毁飞行器的残片
Other witnesses claimed to have seen actual pieces of a crashed spacecraft--
报道称  这些材料超越了当时的科技水平
Materials that are reportedly unknown to science.
阿诺德的目击与罗斯威尔事件
Both Arnold's sighting and the Roswell incident remain
都未得到官方证实  二者本身也颇有争议
officially unconfirmed and highly controversial.
几乎每年都有许多关于不明物体的报道
Just about every year, there are thousands of reported sightings
它们多数出现在空中
mostly in the sky,
便被认为是外星飞船
of objects that they assume are extraterrestrial craft--
即不明飞行物
So-called UFOs.
这个"不明"很关键  因为它们从未被确认过
The "U" is important, of course. They're unidentified.
我本人也曾看到一个从地平线飞起
I personally have seen a bright light start at the horizon
进而直入云霄的亮点
and shoot off into the clouds.
严格来说这就是个不明飞行物
Now, strictly speaking, that was a UFO.
从不明飞行物到外星飞船是一个很大的跨越
It's a big jump between a UFO and an extraterrestrial spacecraft.
科学家认为
Scientists argue that
大部分观察到的不明飞行物要么来自地球
most UFO sightings either have Earthly origins--
例如人造卫星  气球或者飞机
Like satellites, ballons, and aircraft.
要么来自宇宙  如陨石和彗星
Or cosmic origins, such is meteors, comets,
也可能是特别耀眼的  比如金星
or even the specially bright, Planet Venus
但当我们无法解释不明飞行物现象时
But when a UFO sighting has no known explanation,
它会不会就是外星飞船呢
could it be an extraterrestrial craft?
既然如此  究竟何种技术才能够制造出
And if so, what kind of technologies could possibly explain the behaviors
这些目击者所描述的现象
that witnesses actually report?
这些飞行器是如何制成
How would such craft be built?
其间又需要攻克怎样的难题
And what problems would they have to overcome?
报道中所述多种不明飞行物的行为
A lot of the behavior of UFOs that people have reported
都超出了我们目前物理学水平
are things that are beyond our current level of physics--
极快速率  极致加速度与急促转弯速度
Extreme rates of speed or extreme acceleration, extreme turn rates,
这些都是人类目前无法实现的
things that just we're-- we're not capable of doing
否则驾驶员甚至飞行器都要承受巨大损害
without extreme harm to a pilot or destroying a spacecraft.
这些目击者描述了超快的加速度
Eyewitness accounts of super fast accelerations,
闪电般的转向与急停
lightning turns, and sudden stops
这些似乎违反了已知的物理学定律
seem to violate known laws of physics,
但外星人是否已掌握毋须遵守规律的技术呢
but could aliens find a way around these laws?
需要强调的一条是惯性定律
So what we have to keep in mind here is the principle of inertia.
露丝安妮・沃克薇姿
普林斯顿大学
由艾萨克・牛顿首先提出
That principle, stated first by Isaac Newton,
即一个处于静止或运动的物体
says that an object at rest or in motion
只有受外力影响才会改变其初始状态
tends to stay at rest or in motion unless acted on by an outside force.
因此为了适应如此剧烈的惯性变化
So, to generate these kinds of crazy changes in inertia,
就需要对这些物体施加极大的外力
you'd really have to act on that object with an immense amount of force.
例如  一架战斗机飞行员
Following the same logic, a fighter pilot
以近音速的速度飞行
traveling near the speed of sound,
并试图在该速度下  调转90度
attempting to make a 90-degree turn at the same speed,
将承受将近300G的力
would experience something close to 300 "G"S of force.
飞行员穿着压力服时
The most that a human pilot wearing a pressure suit
最多能够承受约10G的力而不至晕厥
can manage without blacking out is around ten "G"S.
如果它的身体构架和人类有几分相似
If his physiology were remotely similar to humans,
进行300G力的转向
an extraelestial pilot undergoing a 300 "G"s maneuvering
会立即导致死亡
would instantly perish.
它的内脏会继续往前运动
His internal organs would continue moving forward
因撞击骨骼而碎裂
and crush against the skeleton.
如果它们跟人类相似
If they were similar to us,
就得知道如何处理液体喷撞
they'd probably have to have a way of ejecting fluid--
就是体内的液体
Internal fluid-- Inside their bodies
这样它们就能解决
so that they dealt with
内脏在体内四处游动的问题
this problem of their organs floating around inside,
如果能固定好内脏  加以适当的缓冲
and if they were strapped in properly and cushioned properly, uh,
在加速或减速时  它们的内脏就不会受损
end up not having internal damage when they accelerated and decelerated.
为有效抵消飞行器本身的惯性作用
To effectively cancel the inertial effects on the craft itself,
这些飞行员需要利用的
the pilots might switch on a technology
是现代人类目前只能叹而观止的技术
that is beyond the reach of modern humans.
为了不受这转弯所带来的300G的影响
So, in order to cancel out the effects of a 300-g turn
并且不会被这巨力所压碎
and not be squished by that amount of force,
你必须要有一种技术或装置
you'd have to have some sort of technology or a device
来抵消惯性作用
that was capable of canceling the effects of inertia.
这个装置能够控制重力效应
The device would have to manipulate the force of gravity,
运用一种力场
using a type of force field
抵消并控制整个宇宙的重力作用
to counteract the gravitational forces that rule the entire universe.
你可以根据需要
This device, you could turn on if you wanted to,
启动或关闭该装置
then turn it off if you wanted to,
或者这个装置能够自动启用和关闭
or maybe it would come on and off automatically.
这项技术远远超出人类的能力
This is high technology that's out of sight.
如果科学解释不了
But if science can't yet explain
这些飞行器如何克服惯性这一关键问题
how these craft could overcome the deadly problem of inertia,
那飞行器的外形又是怎么一回事呢
can it help explain their shapes...
尤其是该如何解释这个最为出名的飞碟形状呢
Particularly the most famous shape of all, the flying saucer?
20世纪50年代末  美国空军测试了飞行车
In the late 1950s, the U.S. Air force tested the Avrocar,
但其设计不稳定  毫无空气动力优势
but the design had poor stability and few aerodynamic advantages,
正好证明碟状飞行器
proving that high speeds are unattainable
无法在地球大气层高速行进
for saucer craft in Earth's atmosphere.
三角翼或者楔形  都比碟形设计更稳定
The delta wing, or wedge shape, is a far stronger candidate--
这是现代军事飞行器设计者所熟知的事实
A fact that is well known by modern military aircraft designers.
事实上  目击楔形不明飞行物的报道数目
In fact, the percentage of UFO sightings reporting a wedge-shaped craft
在近几十年来呈逐年增长趋势
have increased in recent decades,
后掠翼喷气机  甚至是像蝇翅设计的
a trend that mirrors the emergence of swept-wing jets
B2隐形轰炸机则应运而生
and even flying-wing designs like the B-2 stealth bomber.
这些年来人们所报告的飞行器外形一直在改变
The shapes that people have reported over the years have changed,
最近报告的形状基本都是楔形
with the most recent ones being more wedge-shaped.
因此  人们的描述其实反映的是
So, really, people's accounts tend to reflect
当时最先进的飞行器
the most advanced aircraft of the time.
除了运行方式和外形
Beyond movement and shape,
要解开不明飞行物之谜
any attempt to explain the science of UFOs
还牵涉到噪音问题
has to deal with the noise factor,
准确地说  是它完全无噪音现象
or rather, the lack of noisy.
关于不明飞行物的报告均称
UFO reports consistently claim
这些物体在移动过程中没有发出任何声音
that the objects moved without making any sound.
几乎所有的目击报告中都提到
Almost all of these sightings,
它没有半点噪音
it's a real rule-- there's no noise,
但按理说  在地球大气层中
which you would expect to hear from
任何高速运动的飞行器都会产生噪音
any fast-moving craft in the Earth's atmosphere.
人们能够听见
You would hear it.
在实际情况中会产生音爆
What actually happens is that you get what's called a sonic boom,
这是飞行器高速飞行时
and that's a special pressure wave that
克利福德・强森
南加州大学
穿过大气所产生的特殊压力波
sweeps through the atmosphere along with the craft.
当人在地面上所听到
So you're on the ground,
巨大音爆的产生是由于
and that huge sonic boom is the result of that pressure difference
飞行器在穿越大气时
between the front of the aircraft and the back of the aircraft
其首尾压力不同所致
as it pushes through the atmosphere.
外星飞行器能够设法消除超音速飞行中
Could an alien craft somehow cancel out the enormous pressure wave
产生的巨大压力波吗
that supersonic flight generates?
答案也许就在
The answer could lie
最新一代的数码消音耳机所采用的技术中
in the technology used in the latest generation of digital noise-canceling headphones.
消音技术确实存在
So there is such a thing as a sound-canceling technology,
即选取想要消除的声音
where you take a particular sound that you're interested in canceling
之后播放相反的声音  以达到抵消的效果
and kind of broadcast the negative of that sound to cancel it out.
据我所知  现代技术还无法
Now, I'm not aware of any technology that's capable of
抵消冲击波
doing that with shock waves.
要抵消音爆所带来的震耳欲聋的效果
Canceling out the ear-splitting, body-shaking effect of a sonic boom
必然需要一些先进的工程技术
would certainly require some advanced engineering skills.
假设静音已解决  而隐形又该如何解释
And if there is silence, what about invisibility?
一些报道称不明飞行物在天际凭空消失
Some reports claim that UFOs simply disappear into thin air.
现阶段正在研究的一种人类技术
One promising human technology currently being researched
也许能够解释这一现象
might explain such phenomenon.
一种即将问世的技术也许可以改变物体的像
There is a technology on the horizon which might change things visually.
那是一种光线扭曲技术
And that is a kind of light-bending technology.
属于超材料的一种
As a class, they're called metamaterials.
热门电影中有不少展示
If you want to think about popular movies,
例如哈利波特电影中的隐形斗篷
think the invisibility cloak in the Harry Potter movies.
超材料依靠聚合物基质以及金和铜
Metamaterials use combinations of polymer substrates, gold, and copper
有效地扭曲物体周围的电磁波
to forcibly bend electromagnetic waves around an object.
光线被引导绕过物体
The light is guided around the object rather than being
而非反射或折射
reflected or refracted.
若天外来客无法到达地球
But advanced materials, stealth capability,
先进材料  隐形能力
and mind-bending maneuverability would all come to nothing
和超强的机动性都将是纸上谈兵
if our visitors were unable to get to Earth in the first place.
我认为其他文明成功来访的几率
I'd say that the chances of another civilization making it
是非常小的
here to visit us are pretty miniscule.
但如果它们真的做到了
But if they did make it,
那意味着它们已经解决了诸多难题
it would mean that they had solved a whole bunch of problems,
包括我们还无法解答的材料科学问题
including material-science problems that we don't have answers to.
因此他们的技术将领先我们许多
So they'd have technology far beyond ours,
甚至超越了我们想象
perhaps even beyond what we've dreamt of at this point.
科学家推断出了一些独具匠心的技术
But scientists can imagine several ingenious technologies
可以完成这看似不可能完成的星际旅行
that could bridge the seemingly unbridgeable distance between the stars,
包括一种能量巨大的爆炸式推进
including one explosive propulsion source that's so apocalyptic,
可能身在数光年外的我们也能观测到
we might see them coming light years away.
数十年来  无数有关不明飞行物的报道
For decades, countless UFO reports have
从世界各个城市和乡村传来
surfaced from cities and countries around the globe.
但并非所有事件都发生在地球上
But not all UFO sightings have been reported from the surface of planet Earth.
2009年7月19日
On July 19, 2009,
美国宇航局奋进号航天飞机上的视频监视员
viewers of a NASA video feed from the space shuttle endeavor
发现一碟状物体
reported seeing a disc-shaped object
徘徊于太空船的机械臂上方
hovering above the shuttle's mechanical arm.
收到图像  只有9.65公里的距离
Roger that visual, it has only six miles...
此类太空不明飞行物的目击事件
Space-based UFO sightings like this have purportedly happened
在人类航天史上时有发生
throughout the history of manned spaceflight.
无法断定的宇宙现象
Unspecified cosmic phenomenon,
是否就是
or could it suggest the possibility that
大型星际战舰正在银河系中航行
huge extraterrestrial starship are cruising the Milky Way galaxy?
星际旅行  是科幻题材的主要内容
Space travel between the stars-- It's a staple of science fiction, right?
赛斯・肖斯塔科
地外文明搜索研究所
晚间电视节目上能见到
You see it every night on television.
在电影情节中里也常出现
You see it in the movies all the time.
但我们真的能实现吗  有哪种物种做到了
But could we really do it, or could any species really do it?
星际距离非常遥远
Well, the distances between the stars are enormous-- Really enormous.
星际旅行并不违背物理学
Interstellar travel doesn't violate physics.
我们并不能排除其发生的可能性
It isn't that you can rule it out,
说  "它们绝对到不了这里"
and say "There's absolutely no way they can come here."
只是它实现的可能性微乎其微
It's just that it's very, very hard.
以距地球最近的半人马座阿尔法星为例
Just traveling from the Earth to Alpha Centauri,
它与地球的间距有4.5光年
our closest neighboring star at nearly 4 1/2 light years,
超过人类现有最强力火箭的射程
is beyond the reach of our most powerful rockets.
如果遥远星系的先进文明前来访问
If an advanced civilization were to visit us from a distant star system,
它们绝对不会使用化学燃料的火箭
we can pretty much rule out that they would use chemical rockets to get here.
凯文・格雷瑟尔
行星学家
不管阿波罗  土星五号还是航天飞机
Despite the impressive pillar of fire and smoke that we see
发射时有着多么壮丽的火焰和烟雾
during Apollo, Saturn V, or shuttle launches,
化学火箭在太阳系中走不了多远
chemical rockets don't get you very far in a solar system.
作为现存航行最远的空间探测器
To give you some context for that distance,
露丝安妮・沃克薇姿
普林斯顿大学
发射于1977年的旅行者一号的工作是
our furthest known space probe is Voyager 1,
反馈星际间距的信息
launched in 1977.
它以每小时6.1万公里的速度
It's been flying for 34 years
飞行了34年
at 38,000 miles per hour,
而它现在才刚飞离太阳系没多久
and it's only now starting to leave our Solar System.
如果它的目的地是半人马座阿尔法星
If its destination were Alpha Centauri,
则需要超过5.6万年的时间
it would take over 56,000 years
才能到达这最近的星系
to reach even the closest star system.
如果星际旅行可以在人的一生中完成
To engage in interstellar missions on time frames of a human lifetime,
理查德・奥博塞
理论物理学家
时间约为50年
around about 50 years,
可以得出
we can see that
我们的航行速度至少要提高1,000倍
we need to increase the speed that we can travel by at least a factor of 1,000.
科学家已证实
Scientists have determined
光速达到了令人咂舌的每秒三十万公里
that the speed of light is a mind-blowing 186,000 miles per second.
星际飞船若航行于星系之中
A spacecraft traveling the star systems
需要达到光速的相对比重
would have to reach a significant percentage of that speed
才可能到达最近的星系
even to reach the nearest star.
最大的难题就是重量
The biggest obstacle is weight.
化学火箭负载量极大
A chemical rocket exacts a huge weight penalty,
因为它要装载所有的能源供给
because its entire fuel supply must be carried on board.
经计算得出
We can calculate that
仅仅是达到光速6%的
even to reach 6% of the speed of light
化学火箭所需燃料
using chemical rocket fuel,
就得超过整个宇宙的质量
you would need more rocket fuel than exists mass in the universe.
据此可知
So we really know that
光靠化学火箭燃料无法完成星际旅行
it's actually impossible to reach another star system using chemical rocket fuel.
如果外星来访已然实现
If extraterrestrial visitations are even possible,
它们一定解决了燃料问题
their spacecraft must solve this problem.
2011年  美国宇航局的D型纳米帆
In 2011, NASA's Nanosail-D
成为第一艘环绕地球飞行的太阳帆
became the first solar sail to orbit the Earth.
这块9.29平方米的超薄帆利用太阳光
The ultra-thin 100-square-foot sail uses sunlight,
或是光子压力来作为推动力
or photon pressure, as a source of propulsion.
火箭推动不可改变的局限性在于
One of the immutable limitations of rocket propulsion
就是需要随火箭体携带燃料
is the fact that any rocket has to carry its fuel with it.
太阳帆则能利用自然资源的优势
A solar sail can take advantage of the naturally occurring resources,
即太阳发出的光量子
namely photons emanating from the sun,
从而转化为太阳帆的推动力
which can be used to propel that solar sail.
同理  悬挂式滑翔机没有能源或引擎
Similarly, a hang glider can fly without any fuel or an engine
仅仅利用我们身边的自然资源
just by taking an advantage of the natural resources we're surrounded by,
遵循大气流通规律  亦能成行
namely the atmosphere and the laws of aerodynamics.
可载生物飞船要达到足够速度
To achieve sufficient speeds to tow a spacecraft supporting life forms,
需要直径达数百公里的巨型太阳帆
the sail would have to be huge, up to hundreds of miles in diameter.
由于恒星产生的光子压力
And because the photon pressure from a star
会随着太阳帆航行渐远而减弱
would decrease the further the sail traveled,
有人设想过用高聚激光束驱动太阳帆
some have envisioned a concentrated laser beam directing energy at the sail.
但最终无法避免的是
Eventually and sadly,
所有的滑翔机在一定时段后都会降落
this hang glider and all hang gliders at some point have to land,
但使用高聚激光束的太阳帆
but a solar sail riding a beam of laser energy
在理论上可以完成星际旅行
could conceivably travel to the stars.
太阳帆能达到的最大速度
The max speed of a solar sail--
约为光速的10%
About 10% the speed of light.
最大速度  每秒三万公里
靠激光光子能量从地球到半人马座阿尔法星
Travel from Earth to Alpha Centauri using laser-generated photons--
大约需45年
About 45 years.
最大速度  每秒3万公里
到达半人马座阿尔法星时长  45年
当前  美国宇航局及其他航天机构
Currently, NASA and other space agencies
计划发射更多的太阳帆
have plans for launching more solar sails.
但宇宙中还有其他更强大的动力源
But there are other, more powerful sources of propulsion in the universe.
十九世纪六十年代有人提出一种推进方法
In the 1960s, a method of propulsion was proposed
即在飞船尾部
where a spacecraft would literally
安置一系列爆炸物
drop a series of explosive charges out the back,
爆炸带来的能量将推动飞船前进
and the force of the explosions would push the spacecraft forward.
原型机被称作"核脉冲推进"
The prototype was called the "Orion Drive,"
实际上人们进行了一系列常规炸药的试验
And there were actually a series of experiments done with conventional charges
以证明这是可行的
to show that it would work.
然而"核脉冲推进"燃料使用的是核弹
The Orion Drive, however, was proposed to use nuclear charges.
为模拟核脉冲形式的推进系统
In order to simulate an Orion-style propulsion system,
保罗和吉姆正在搭建示范装置
Paul and Jim here are rigging up a demonstration
他们将少量化学炸药装入罐中
where they're going to put a small chemical charge inside this barrel,
将其炸到约15至18米的空中
and we're going to lift this off the ground 50, 60 feet in the air.
我们将计算这次爆炸释放的能量
We're going to actually calculate the energy released in this explosion
并将其同实际的核脉冲飞船系统中的
and compare it to a nuclear charge you might find on an actual
核爆能量进行比较
Orion Spacecraft system.
核脉冲飞船模拟器已准备就绪
Our Orion spacecraft simulator is rigged and ready to go.
我们将在内部燃火  使其在空中爆炸
We're going to light off the charges inside, blow the can up into the air,
将其与核脉冲形式推进中
and compare that with the energy release from a
核爆炸所产生的能量进行比较
typical nuclear explosion that would be used on an Orion-style drive.
十九世纪五十年代后期
The Orion Spacecraft,
洛斯阿拉莫斯国家实验室所研制的核脉冲飞船
studied at Los Alamos in the late 1950s,
计划将核裂变作为推动力能源
proposed nuclear fission as its propulsion source.
裂变能量来自于原子核分解时
Fission energy is produced when the nucleus of an atom splits into smaller parts,
释放出中子与质子
producing free neutrons and protons
并产生大量的伽马射线能量
and release tremendous γ ray energy.
炸药使这个重达16公斤的罐子
The explosive charge in this 35-pound barrel
冲到高空约18米处
lofted it about 60 feet in the air.
而在广岛着陆的小型核弹能够
A small nuclear charge in the Hiroshima range would liberate
释放出约2,700万倍的能量
about 27 million times more energy.
显而易见  这是保证星体间航行
Clearly, that's a practical propulsion drive for
甚至星际航行的推进驱动力
interplanetary or even interstellar travel.
由于飞船尾部核脉冲推进需要大爆炸的冲击力
Because of the huge explosions that an Orion Drive would require, on the back of the spacecraft,
用以吸收爆炸冲击力的大块厚实金属板
you would have a huge, thick metal plate that would absorb the thrust of the explosion
以及一系列的冲击波吸收器便是不可缺少的
and a series of shock absorbers to keep the crews from
它们将船员与爆炸后的余震隔离
getting jolted each time the charges went off.
核裂变能源飞船的最大速度
The max speed of a nuclear-powered fission spacecraft--
大约是光速的5%
About 5% the speed of light.
最大速度  每秒1.5万公里
从地球到半人马座阿尔法星
Travel time from Earth to Alpha Centauri--
大约需要90年
About 90 years.
最大速度  每秒1.5万公里
到达半人马座阿尔法星时长  90年
若不是能量来源十分强大
Despite its powerful fuel source,
裂变飞船比还太阳帆要慢
the fission craft is actually slower than a solar sail.
加快速度意味着
Boosting speed would mean
它需要另种更剧烈的核反应
turning to another, more intense nuclear reaction.
人们熟知核裂变技术
Fission technology is well known and understood.
使用其制造能源已有几十年
And we've been using it to generate power here on Earth for decades,
但还存在另一种核技术
But there is another kind of nuclear technology,
即核聚变
and that is nuclear fusion.
太阳的能量来自于核聚变
Fusion is the power source of the Sun.
太阳核心的温度非常高
In the core of our Sun, the temperatures are so high,
原子们的剧烈运动导致其互相撞击
atoms are moving so fast that they slam into each other,
产生新的元素并释放能量
creating new elements and liberating energy.
与裂变相反
The opposite of fission,
当两个原子熔合成单个新超重原子时
fusion energy is produced when two atomic nuclei fuse together
就产生了聚变能
to form a single heavier nuclear.
从而释放出巨大能量
The result is a huge liberation of energy.
十九世纪七十年代的"戴德拉斯工程"
A fusion-powered spacecraft was proposed in a 1970s study
计划研究聚变能飞船
called "Project Daedelus."
其任务是造访巴纳德星
It's mission called for a trip to Barnard's star,
距地球约5.9光年
some 5.9 light years distant.
与核弹不同的是
Instead of nuclear bombs,
核聚能太空船的推进力
the fusion-powered craft creates the propulsion
源于一个反应箱
on board in a reaction chamber.
戴德拉斯级太空船的燃料球芯块
The fuel pellets for the Daedelus class starship
由氘-氦3的混合芯块组成
consisted of pellets composed of a deuterium-helium-3 mix.
由相对论性电子束激发
These would have been ignited by what we call relativistic electron beams.
这些含有极高能量的电子
These are extremely high energy electrons
击中氘-氦-3芯块
that would have hit the deuterium-helium-3 pellets,
致使它们融合
caused them to fuse,
并释放出大量能量
and a huge amount of energy would be released.
戴德拉斯需要二百五十个这样的芯块
The Daedelus design called for 250 of these pellets
在超过两年的时段中不间断地释放能量
to be released every second for over two years.
太空船将重达五万五千吨
The spacecraft would have weighed 55,000 tons,
其中绝大部分是燃料
most of which would have been fuel.
这个重量对宇宙飞船来说未免太大
The weight penalty for such a spacecraft would be high
但有一种先进技术能解决这个问题
but an advanced civilization could eliminate the problem
即在星际旅行过程中开采氢燃料
by mining the hydrogen fuel during its interstellar journey.
氘  或说重氢
Deuterium, or heavy hydrogen,
在地球上储量丰富
exists in abundance on Earth,
尤其是在海水中
notably in seawater,
但氦3则是更为罕见的同位素
but helium-3 is a much rarer isotope.
它存在于太阳系的月球上
In our Solar System, it can be found on the Moon
在木星和土星上的含量则极为丰富
and in vast quantities on Jupiter and Saturn.
科学家们提议在穿越物资匮乏的空间时
Scientists have proposed using huge hydrogen scoops
使用巨型集氢器来开采氦3
to mine the helium-3 needed to cross the void of space.
请试想
So it's conceivable
如果你有一艘核聚能太空船
that if you had a craft that was powered by nuclear fusion,
进入另一恒星系统时
you could go to another star system,
可以利用那颗星球上的氢来补充燃料
and then use the hydrogen available from that star to refuel.
设备齐全的聚合能太空船
The self-contained fusion-powered spacecraft
因而可以避免负载巨大的重量
could avoid a huge weight penalty
并以一定速度
and reach speeds
在适当的时段内进行近恒星探测
that could allow near-star exploration in a reasonable time frame.
核聚能太空船的最大速度
The max speed of a nuclear-powered fusion spacecraft--
最大速度  每秒4.7万公里
能达到光速的百分之十五
up to 15% of the speed of light.
从地球到半人马座阿尔法星
Travel time from Earth to Alpha Centauri--
最大速度  每秒4.7万公里
到达半人马座阿尔法星时长  约35年
约需三十五年
about 35 years.
核动力航天的巨额花费  所需物流支持
The immense costs, the logistics,
甚至国家政策在很久以前
and even the politics of nuclear-powered spaceflight
使得所有计划迟迟未能运行
long ago caused humanity to scrap any and all plans.
但是一个足够先进的文明社会
But a sufficiently advanced society
能够利用核动力
could trade nuclear propulsion
达成那些看似不可能的事
for what seems like an impossible paradox--
以光速达到瞬间位移
Traveling at light speed without moving at all.
UFO真能以高速
Can UFOs actually achieve the immense speeds
完成星际旅行吗
required for interstellar travel?
答案也许就埋藏在
One potential answer may be buried
美国核心地带的三十英尺之下
30 feet beneath the ground in America's heartland...
就在伊利诺斯州芝加哥郊外的
the Fermilab Tevatron Collider
费米实验室电子伏对撞机
outside Chicago, Illinois.
稍慢于光速的质子和反质子
Racing just below the speed of light, particles of protons and antiproton
分别由相反的方向发射
are launched in opposing directions.
以高能对撞形式结合
They meet in a high energy collision.
这种撞击产生的伽马射线
The impact produces gamma rays--
是宇宙最强的能量源
the highest energy source known in the universe
也是实现星际旅行的可能性关键
and potentially the key to interstellar travel.
在地球上制造反物质的最佳方法
The best way of making antimatter here on Earth
克利福德・强森
南加州大学
就是采用
is to employ probably
爱因斯坦最为出名的方程式
the most famous equation that Einstein taught us,
即质能方程
which is E=mc2,
说明一定的质量是可以产生能量的
which tells us that for a certain amount of matter, we can get energy.
这个理论因其实际影响重大而意义非凡
It's a great idea because it's incredibly efficient.
可以把粒子中所有的质量转化成能量
You essentially take all of the mass in those particles and convert it into energy.
但如果反物质必须由人为产生
But how can antimatter exist in the universe
它怎么会存在于宇宙中呢
if it must be artificially manufactured?
这是来自费城的史蒂芬・H
That's the question that Stefan H. from Philadelphia
向宇宙提出的质疑
texted the Universe.
反物质是否存在  我们将如何观测
史蒂芬・H  宾夕法尼亚州费城
史蒂芬  反物质是一定存在的
Stefan, antimatter definitely exists,
当它接触普通物质
and when it meets up with normal matter,
爆发出强大的电磁辐射
it explodes in a burst of electromagnetic radiation.
我们可以在实验室制造少量反物质
Now, we can make small bits of antimatter in laboratories,
但也可以从太空中收集
but we can also collect antimatter from space.
某些带电的宇宙光
Some cosmic rays, which are charged,
来自太空的高能粒子
very energetic particles coming from space,
的确是由反物质组成
actually consist of antimatter.
目前  超级对撞机是唯一
Currently, the super-collider is the only
在实际中生产反物质的方法
practical way to produce antimatter.
而如今它的数量有限
And right now it's created in very small quantities.
如果我们能找到
If we could figure out a way
生产和储存大量反物质的方法
to both create and store enough antimatter,
威廉・R・阿尔舒勒
加利福尼亚人文研究所
我们将拥有一种可储存的燃料
we would have a storable fuel which,
当它和普通物质混合时
when mixed with ordinary matter,
将释放出巨大能量
would liberate a huge amount of energy
比核裂变或是核聚合更有效
at a rate way beyond what either fission or fusion can do.
因为反物质是存在于世的
Because we know antimatter exists
我们可以生产并将其储存
and we know antimatter can be created and stored,
也许某种先进文明
it is conceivable that an advanced civilization
理查德・奥伯塞
理论物理学家
可以生产并利用反物质能量
could create and harness the power of antimatter
用其制造一枚反物质火箭
in sufficient quantities to create an antimatter rocket.
一艘反物质飞船可以达到不可思议的速度
An antimatter ship could achieve unbelievable velocities,
仅次于光速
cruising just below light speed,
与穿过银河系的粒子束速度不相上下
nearly matching the speed of a star beam streaking across the galaxy.
从地球到半人马座阿尔法星的行程时间
Travel time from Earth to Alpha Centauri
最大速度  每秒28.5万公里
即通过4.5光年的路程
4 1/2 light years distant--
最大速度  每秒28.5万公里
到达半人马座阿尔法星时长  5年
大约需要5年
about 5 years.
人类无法想象
In human terms,
生产足够的反物质微粒
the cost of creating enough antimatter particles
来运作这样一艘星际飞船所需经费
to power such a starship would be astronomical.
也许外星人财力雄厚  足以承担
It might be affordable in alien currency,
但制造一艘反物质太空船所需代价太大
but an antimatter spacecraft like this comes at a high price.
来自于反物质动力的伽马射线危害极大
The gamma rays from antimatter propulsion are so dangerous,
它们会摧毁飞船上所有生物细胞结构
they could destroy the cell structure of any living beings aboard ship.
星际飞船上必须有一个先进的防护装置
This starship would have to include an advanced shielding mechanism
以保障船员的生命安全
to keep the crew alive.
其行驶速度飞快
And at such high rates of speed,
对宇宙有一定破坏作用
there are equally destructive threats in the universe.
宇宙空间浩瀚无边
Space is pretty empty,
但如果以近光速行驶于其中
but if you were moving close to the speed of light,
露丝安妮・沃克薇姿
普林斯顿大学
就需要一个极佳的防护系统
you'd need an extremely effective shielding system
免其遭受星际尘粒的破坏
that would allow you to be protected from interstellar dust particles
它们几乎可以摧毁一艘光速行驶的太空船
that would all but annihilate a spacecraft traveling that fast.
但是如果太空垃圾如此危险
But if space debris is so dangerous,
何不避而远之呢
why not avoid it completely?
解决方案和星际迷航粉丝的想法有些类似
The solution might be one familiar to Star Trek fans,
即星际飞船
namely a starship that
以光速达成瞬间位移
could achieve light speed without even moving.
实际上可以制造一种曲速泡
In effect, one would create what is called a "Warp bubble"--
这名字源于科幻小说
the name taken straight out of science fiction--
就是当一艘太空船稳坐于这个扁平泡内
and that would involve compressing a region of space-time in front of a spacecraft
将太空船前某一范围内的时空压缩
and expanding a region of space-time behind a spacecraft
并扩大其后某范围内的时空
while the spacecraft itself sat stationary inside this flat bubble.
如此就能有效地驾驭时空波浪
So one would effectively be riding a wave of space-time.
曲速引擎就像一种纯粹理想化的实验状态
A warp drive may seem like pure Sci-Fi fantasy...
但在1994年  一位广受尊重的年轻物理学家
But in 1994, a well-respected young physicist
米给尔・阿库别瑞
named Miguel Alcubierre
发表了一份重大提议概述
published a serious proposal outlining
曲速引擎  广义相对论范围内的超速旅行
如何在受控的空间扭曲穿梭
how to travel in a controllable space warp.
阿库别瑞的曲速引擎还存在许多难题
There are huge obstacles to Alcubierre's warp-drive solution.
最大的障碍便是"暗能量"
The biggest is called "Dark energy"...
有三位科学家在2011年
A cosmic phenomenon recognized in 2011
发现并证明了这一宇宙现象
when three scientists were awarded the Nobel prize
并因此获得诺贝尔奖
for proving its existence.
关于暗能量现象
The simplest explanation that's been proposed
最简单的解释就是
for the phenomenon of dark energy is that
空间自身的固有特性
there's an intrinsic property of space itself
令其趋向扩张膨胀
that makes it want to expand.
通过观察宇宙已逝去的时空
You can actually see it by looking at receding parts of the universe
以及额外的加速度便可知晓
and seeing that there's this extra acceleration component,
但又不像太阳能或其他能源
but it isn't a stored energy source
它并非可储存能源
like solar energy or other kinds of energy.
所以它也不是那么匪夷所思
And so it's not inconceivable--
宇宙某个角落
it's not beyond the realms of possibility
应该存在某种先进文明
that some advanced civilization
已然将暗能量技术谙熟于心
existing somewhere in the universe has learned
并利用其制造另种形式的动力
how to harness dark energy to create an exotic form of propulsion.
但实际上  曲速引擎还存在另一个障碍
But there's another obstacle to a workable warp drive.
利用扭曲将太空船往前推动的唯一办法
The only known way to pull a spacecraft forward within a warp
需要利用黑洞的剧烈能量
requires harnessing the intense energy of a black hole.
简单来说就是
The sort of simple notion is somehow
用某种方法制造一种高浓缩物质
to make a very concentrated bit of matter,
极度浓缩至可以产生黑洞
extremely concentrated, on the level which would cause a black hole.
如果能制造出一个小型黑洞
If you could generate a black hole on a small scale, so to speak,
让它悬浮在飞船前方
you could dangle it in front of the ship
利用它的空间扭曲拖动飞船缓缓前行
and use its space distortion to sort of drag the ship along.
由曲速引擎推动的外星飞船
And exactly how fast could a warp drive tow
到底有多快
an extraterrestrial spacecraft?
阿库别瑞在文中明显提出了以下观点
The clear implication of Alcubierre's work was that it should be possible,
如果你能设计出曲速引擎
if you can make this design of a warp drive,
其速度就能达到光速的任意倍
to achieve speeds almost any multiple of the speed of light.
一艘由空间扭曲驱动的光速飞船
Travel time from Earth to Alpha Centauri
从地球到半人马座阿尔法星的时间
aboard a light speed craft powered by a space warp--
最大速度  每秒至少29.9万公里
约四年半
about 4 1/2 years...
最大速度  每秒至少29.9万公里
到达半人马座阿尔法星时长  至多4.5年
只要能保障船内人员安全  时间可以更短
or less, as long as everyone on board doesn't incinerate.
阿库别瑞的引擎存在一个问题
One problem with the Alcubierre drive is within that warp bubble,
凯文・格雷瑟尔
行星学家
曲速泡中的温度远比太阳内核要高
temperatures would rise to far hotter than the core of our Sun.
非常热
That's hot.
到达地球之前还有一个小问题
Just one more small problem to solve for the chance to reach planet Earth.
如果一艘将要抵达地球大气层的外星飞船
But what if such an alien spacecraft were to arrive in earth's atmosphere,
在曲速泡中行驶
riding in a warp bubble,
被黑洞拖着呢
towed by a black hole?
即使这并非拥有众多目击证人的首例
It might not be the first mass-witness UFO sighting,
但一定会是最后一次
but it would certainly be the last.
1997年3月13日
March 13, 1997...
成千上万人目睹了一次光学现象
thousands of people witness an optical phenomenon
漂浮在亚利桑那州的上空
drifting across the Arizona skies.
有关几何形亮点的消息传得沸沸扬扬
Reports of a series of bright lights in geometric patterns are widespread,
包括多人目睹一艘身长1.6公里
including multiple sightings over Phoenix
并伴有规律性灯光闪烁的太空船
of a craft up to a mile wide with lights
出现在凤凰城上空
winking on and off in sequence.
重现当晚的景象
Reconstructing the events of that evening,
那次凤凰城的闪烁灯光就是
the lights of the phoenix lights were almost certainly
凯文・格雷瑟尔
行星学家
空军战机A-10抛出的信号弹
flares dropped by an air force A-10 aircraft,
加之人类会将其联想为一个实体外形
in conjunction with the human tendency to envision a solid shape connecting them.
这才是凤凰城灯光事件的最好解释
That's the best explanation for the Phoenix lights.
对很多人来说  凤凰城灯光事件正是
For many, the Phoenix lights incident was
巨型宇宙飞船曾造访此地的直接佐证
direct proof that a huge extraterrestrial craft had arrived.
有人甚至将其称为母舰
Some even called it a mother ship.
母舰存在的目的
The purpose of an extraterrestrial mother ship
是外星人造访理论的基础
is fundamental to the theories of alien visitation.
这是穿越星际空间中遥远距离的唯一方式
It's the only way to bridge the vast distances of interstellar space.
"母舰"这一说法
The term "Mother ship," I think,
威廉・R・阿尔舒勒
《不明飞行物之科学》作者
和"飞碟"这个词是在同一时期出现的
came into being around the same time that "Flying saucers" as a term came into being.
大众普遍认为
And I think the universal notion
仅能容下一人的航空器无法完成星际旅行
was you couldn't make an interstellar trip in a person-sized craft.
一定得是巨型飞船
You have to have something really large.
母舰就如地球上的航空母舰一样
An apt earthly analogy of a mother ship is that of an aircraft carrier.
理查德・奥博塞
理论物理学家
航空母舰穿梭于大洋之间
An aircraft carrier travels the vast distances across the oceans,
其目的则是运载小型战机
but its purpose is to transport smaller aircraft which
这样它们便可执行任务等等
can then go on and engage in whatever their missions may be.
如果需要成百上千年才能抵达地球
If the journey to Earth is long, on the order of centuries or even millennia,
母舰会比航空母舰有更多的功能
the mother ship would be much more than just an aircraft carrier.
这是一艘"方舟"
There's the generational or "Ark ship,"
它是一艘拥有独立生态系统的巨型飞船
Which is a very large spacecraft that is essentially an enclosed ecosystem,
居民会在船舱内生老病死
in which generations of inhabitants expect to be born, grow old, and die
直至很长时间后抵达最终目的地
over the long period it takes the spacecraft to reach its ultimate destination.
利用"假死"技术
Perhaps with technology, such as suspended animation,
外星乘客会进入睡眠状态
biological alien passengers could be put to sleep
直到长途旅行结束时再苏醒
and revived after the vast journey.
若要在这一航行中幸存下来
Surviving such a journey would also mean
就要能承受住推动飞船航行的破坏性能量
surviving the destructive energy powering the spacecraft itself.
其中一种合理的设计
One logical design solution,
是雪茄形的母舰
a cigar-shaped mother ship,
正是众多不明飞行物目击者声称所看到的
is precisely what many UFO witnesses claim to have seen.
对任何一种先进动力系统来说
For any advanced propulsion system,
都会尽可能让船员远离
you would want to situate the crew as far away as possible
引擎动力源
from the engine source.
所以飞船都是极细长的设计
So one possible design would be a very long, thin design,
引擎置于在飞船尾端
with the engine located at one end of the spacecraft
其间用某种框架将船员区尽可能地
and then some kind of truss connecting the crew section
与这种先进动力装置隔开
as far away as possible
以避免高能中子
so as to avoid damage from high-energy neutrons,
X射线以及伽玛射线对人体的损害
x-rays, or gamma rays from the advanced propulsion system.
倘若此种方舟曾抵达地球
If such ark ships have in fact visited planet earth,
它们所留下的痕迹则是无法磨灭的
the evidence would be overwhelming and undeniable.
所有外星先进的推进技术有一个共同点
Something all these exotic and advanced propulsion technologies have in common
即它们都能辐射出巨大能量
is that they all radiate prodigious amounts of energy,
因此就算隔了几光年的距离
and so we'd be able to see them,
我们也能观测到
like beacons on a lighthouse,
就像灯塔上的信号灯一样
from sometimes light years away.
X射线束  伽玛射线束
The concentrated emission of x-rays, gamma rays,
甚至次原子微粒团都是可疑现象
or subatomic particles would be suspicious,
因为这些都不是地球上
'cause we don't see that in our environment locally
所常见的现象
under any normal circumstances.
除去肉眼所能见到的迹象
Beyond the obvious visual evidence,
一艘母舰
the physical effect of a mother ship
靠近地球表面所产生的物理效应
approaching so close to the Earth's surface
能导致一场大灾难
could be a terrifying form of apocalypse.
若出于某种原因
If, for whatever reason,
该外星文明没有关闭引擎
this extraterrestrial technology or civilization chose not to turn off their engines,
地球生物则会经历一场浩劫
it could be catastrophic for life on Earth,
受到高能中子  X射线以及伽玛射线的荼毒
as we would be bathed in high-energy neutrons, x-rays, and gamma rays.
若是某种"曲速飞行"
If it's something which is a version of a warp drive,
那么就会产生空间畸变
then you're talking about space distortion, and
就不能接近大质量的物体  包括星球
you wouldn't want to be too close to any major mass, including the planet.
这种劫难访问说认为
Such catastrophic visitations assume that
外星人甘愿舍身于外太空只为造访地球
aliens are willing to risk their own lives in interstellar space...
但是或许还有更好的方法
But there might be a better way...
他们可以待在自己的星球上
They could stay at home...
利用智能机器人来探索宇宙奥秘
and explore the cosmos using a race of thinking machines.
对于不明飞行物的众多狂热爱好者来说
For many ardent believers in the UFO phenomenon,
1947年夏  美国新墨西哥州罗斯威尔
the Roswell, New Mexico, event in the summer of 1947
罗斯威尔
市区范围
高空3570
是人类史上首次接触外星人
is the defining alien encounter in human history.
民间传闻中  有关这次坠毁事件
In popular culture, the most lasting detail from the purported crash
最持久不衰的是发现了外星尸体的消息
came from the descriptions of extraterrestrial bodies found at the scene.
随后几十年里  这种想象中的"灰种人"
In the ensuing decades, this vision of alien beings, known as "The grays,"
常出现在科幻小说中
Became the accepted standard in science fiction
或是外星人事件报道里
and recurring alien-encounter reports.
硕大的头部也许解释了
The oversized heads may explain
我们所预料的外星人特征  即它们智商过人
an expected feature in alien biology-- Greater intelligence.
与人类相比  头骨越大脑容量越大
The larger skulls would contain larger, more advanced brains
大脑更发达
compared to ours.
在星际航行中要解决棘手问题
Mastering the profound challenges of interstellar travel
固然需要更加智能的物种
would certainly require great intelligence,
但它还需要超出有机生物系统的元素吗
but might it require something that is beyond organic biology?
科幻小说中包含的误重大误区
One area of science fiction where we might be making kind of a big mistake
赛斯・肖斯塔科
地外文明搜索研究所
即我们将外星人臆想成某种生物体
is to assume that the aliens are biological, that they're living things.
我认为  有很多种有机体
I think that the possibilities for the kinds of organisms
威廉・R・阿尔舒勒
加利福尼亚人文研究所
可以进行星际航行
which might travel between the stars are really wide open.
可能在科幻小说中所提及的
And one possibility that has appeared on occasion in
实际上是指智能机器人
science fiction is machine intelligence.
根据近期出现的方程  即摩尔定律
According to a recent earthly equation known as Moore's Law,
单机芯片上的晶体管数量
the number of transistors on a single computer chip
每18个月增加一倍
doubles every 18 months,
意味着计算机处理速率也会快一倍
meaning computer processing speed doubles.
这种趋势已持续了半个世纪以上
This trend has continued for more than half a century and
至少要延至2020年以后
is expected to continue through 2020 or later.
处理速率的爆炸式增长
The exponential explosion of processing speed
为以"人工智能"为题材的科幻小说
is opening the door on a staple of science fiction
开启了一道大门
called "Artificial Intelligence."
如果你发明了一台智能机器  一百年之后
So, if you invent a thinking machine, 100 years later,
它不止是比你要聪明
that machine is not only smarter than you are,
它还比此前任何人都要聪明
it's smarter than all humans that have ever lived.
这就是人工智能
And that's the difference
与真正人的智力之间的差别
between artificial intelligence and real intelligence.
人工智能能够飞速进化
Artificial intelligence can evolve enormously faster.
但最令我们担心又期待的在于
But I think the form of AI that we find most both menacing and promising
人工智能既能够像人脑般运作
is the kind of AI that could in fact do what our brains can do,
又具备人类的思维
can think the way we can think.
在斯坦福大学的人工智能实验室中
At Stanford university's artificial intelligence laboratory,
智能机器的发展趋势就是这种倾向
the future of truly intelligent machines is rapidly approaching.
以下难点使得人工智能变得十分棘手
There are a few things that make AI difficult.
即我们不知如何去改进计算机
One is we don't really know yet how to make computers learn as
让它的学习效率变得和人类一样
effectively as humans can.
似乎现代计算机运行速度受限仅仅是因为
It seems that our computers today just aren't as fast as we
人类不愿让它们模仿其认知过程
would like them to get to simulate the learning processes
进而取代人脑
that take place in the human brain.
人工智能实验室
斯坦福的学生设计了一台击打型机器臂
To demonstrate early-stage artificial intelligence,
来演示人工智能研究的初期成效
Stanford students designed a fighting robot--
是一台在击打中学习的智能机
One that attempts to learn as it fights.
它现在在做的是  自我防守
Okay, so what it's doing now-- It's trying to defend itself,
它会随着您的动作作出反应
so it's reacting to your motion.
即这个机器人会根据您手中剑的走向
So, depending on how you move your sword,
对您的动作行为作出反应
the robot will adapt to your motion and to your behavior.
研发此类机器人对于真正人工智能的意义
How important a step on the road to true artificial intelligence
有多深远呢  托尔斯滕
are robots like this, Torsten?
我们在这里运用的人工智能方案
So here we are using artificial-intelligence methods,
比如认知方案  是让机器人适应其周围环境
like learning methods, to adapt to the environment of the robot,
但我们对机器人的真实想法无从了解
but we are still not at a stage where the robot is really thinking.
现代计算机的智能依旧不及普通人类
Today's computers are still far less intelligent than almost any human.
但着眼于未来  我相信计算机最终
But in the future, I think computers could eventually
能达到甚至超越人类智力
reach, and maybe even surpass, human intelligence.
倘若真到了这一步  设想每人的钱包里
And if that's the case, imagine that each of us has a computer
都有台电脑  在手机或钱包里都可以
in our wallet--a cell phone or wallet--
智力能与爱因斯坦相抗衡  甚至超越他
That was as smart as Einstein or even smarter.
整个文明将会怎样变化
How will civilization change,
那时的人类又会做出怎样的创举呢
and what are the amazing things we could do then?
这种击打型机器人引领世界尖端科技
Advanced as it is on Earth, the fencing robot is
它是能够适用于星际航空器中的
but a crude analogy for the type of machine intelligence that
人工智能机的简单模拟
could pilot an interstellar spacecraft.
智能机的革新将首次接触
The immense obstacles of space travel,
星际航行中的大问题
including the sheer time scale and cosmic hazards,
包括时标偏离及宇宙无尽凶险
build a strong case that a race of intelligent machines will make first contact.
但话说回来  倘若真的存在星际航行一说
But honestly, if interstellar travel really takes place,
送出非生物体才是明智之举
it seems sort of reasonable to not send the biological beings.
因为生物体的生命力有限  经不起这样的折腾
I mean, they're fragile. They have finite lifetimes.
在美国宇航局领先于人类探索
Just as NASA sends robotic probes to explore the Solar
将勘探机器人送去探测太阳系之际
System in advance of human explorers,
兴许我们会通过外星来的勘探机器人
our first contact with an alien civilization
凯文・格雷瑟尔
行星学家
与异星文明发生首次碰触
may be with its robotic probes.
它究竟是生物体还是人工智能体
Biologic being or AI super being?
我们的憧憬在与其首次接触前
Our vision of an extraterrestrial will remain
都属于纯粹的臆测
mere speculation until first contact is made.
但我们要等多久呢
But how long will we wait?
撇开缺失确凿证据不说
And despite a lack of hard evidence,
异域智慧文明
just how likely is the
存在的可能性有多大呢
existence of another intelligent civilization?
有人确信
Some believe it is highly likely
宇宙每个角落都有生物存在的迹象
that the universe teems with life.
银河星系存在了很长时间
The galaxy has been around for a long time.
太阳系虽是悠久
The Solar System's been around for quite a long time,
但也不及它的历史久远
but the galaxy much longer.
银河系中的星体
And the stars in it--
有许多比太阳和太阳系都要古老
Many of them are much older than the Sun and our Solar System.
所以  如果存在异星文明
So the chances are, if civilizations are out there,
它们应该比人类文明要源远流长得多
they've been around for longer than we have.
倘若真的存在  就说有十万年了吧
If they exist, say, for 100,000 years,
这种异域文明间的碰触几率就非常大了
then the chances are pretty good, I think,
它们应该掌握了 能在宇宙间交流的方式
they will have learned to either communicate
甚至是星际航行技术
across interstellar space or possibly travel.
而在首次接触之前
Until first contact occurs,
人类只能继续仰望星空搜寻不明飞行物
humanity will continue to scan the skies for UFOs.
目前依然无从证明外星飞船的存在
None have been proven to be extraterrestrial craft so far,
但这并不是否认人类总有一天会
but that does not rule out the possibility that humanity may
发现智慧文明存在的痕迹
one day discover evidence of an intelligent civilization,
也许它就在苍穹尽头的某处
they were on heavens,
更靠近它们家园的地方
or much closer to home.